So we woke up one morning and we have a PR that's burnt about $600,
because both those agents were doing exactly what we had told them to do.
And there wasn't this concept of like, hey, this is far enough.
These are kind of like built in processes and built in assumptions and built
in ways of doing engineering work as humans that we have learned over time
that these agents don't know.
Rather than trying to say, like, hey, we need to build into the harness
this assumption of like how you do better code review or how you push back.
It's like, no, let's change the way that we are constructing this system.
So we're here
today to talk about ROI and agentic workflows.
So basically return on investment.
How do we think about it here at Tessl?
How do we improve it?
And most importantly, where do we think most of the ROI that you can get
with today's models in today's agents comes from? So,
I'm Rob, I lead research here at Tessl, and we've been working a lot
on our internal software factory.
So that's where the majority of work at Tessl engineering goes through.
So we're at kind of 80% of all PRs
going through our internal software factory.
And really the most interesting
thing about that was we don't do anything on the agent or harness side.
And when I say agent, what I mean specifically here is coding harness
plus model.
We just use what comes out of the box from Anthropic or OpenAI or Google.
All of our investments to get a working software factory
have been on everything else that surrounds that agent.
So I'm going to start this off with some numbers.
We have our own internal code review tool,
which we've also released out externally.
And we have our own internal agent that does PR updates.
So hey, you push a PR up, you got a code review back.
You then want to address it and push an update up.
And then you get another code review back and iterate.
And so we woke up one morning and we have a PR that's burned about $600,
because both those agents were doing exactly what we had told them to do.
The PR update agent was, you know, updating and response
to PR comments, and the review agent was reviewing those.
And there wasn't this concept of like, hey, this is far enough, or hey,
the scope of this ticket is exactly just targeting this.
And maybe this thing that you
found in a related code file that happened to end up in your context
because one line was changed.
Maybe file a ticket or do something else there.
These are kind of like built in processes and built in assumptions and built
in just ways of doing engineering work as humans that we have learned over time
that these agents don't know because we give them a task, update the PR
and another task, go review the PR and then they'll just go do that.
And so that layer, that context, that intent, that kind of
outside of the agent layer, that's where this issue arose,
because agents were doing what we told them to do.
But then also where we tried to fix it, rather than trying to say, like, hey,
we need to build into the harness this assumption of like how you do better
code review or how you push back.
It's like, no, let's change the way that we are constructing the system.
So when I think about kind of like what the factory is
and how we deliver software, we've got kind of like five stages here.
One is what is a useful task.
So this is work that is valuable to us as a company,
either in terms of experimentation or in terms of product
work, or in terms of any work that a software engineer does to
what is the shared context
in the working environment that this task is being done in the shared context
is everything within our
the environment is something that has spun up
with our dev dependencies, with tests, with creds,
so they can actually test and exercise and verify.
Then there's the agent execution bit. That bit's
Pretty dead simple.
We give it a dev sandbox and we run it in YOLO mode on that sandbox.
And we want to audit.
And then we get things out at the other end.
Then there's the verification and delivery. Cool,
I've got this PR or I've got this code out.
How do I then trust that that is good or good enough or to whatever quality bar
without kind of
degrading into these cycles that we saw with a review agent earlier on.
And then finally, and I think most importantly,
how do I make this loop better the next time?
And so what is the feedback
that I can derive from how that agent completed its task,
or how that agent failed to complete its task,
or where that agent went wrong in terms
of completing its tasks, even if it recovered.
That then lets me improve the whole system overall.
Sneak preview:
I actually think that last one is the most important bit,
and where the vast majority of our efforts go to,
because if we can figure out a way to be automatically ingesting
these feedback loops and then having the system improve itself
based off the failure modes that it's seeing,
then it kind of takes care of the rest of these because it will see the failures.
It will see kind of, hey, this task doesn't have enough context.
And so we need to update our create issues
skills to give it more context and interview
the user more or receivable missing this kind of verification layer
within our factory because this PR always gets rejected.
Yes. Output feeding back into input,
but not even in the loop at the beginning of all chaos.
Oh yes.
I'd say our experience is
not so far.
I can't guarantee in the fullness of time that it won't degenerate into chaos.
But for.
So our internal factory is called Kikimora,
and for the codebase of Kikimora itself, the code that runs our factory.
We have auto merge on and no human review required.
So last time I looked, 95% of the code had never had a human look at it
and was being generated by agents looking at these loops to fix issues
or address features that had come up in Slack
or discussion and then go landing it fully autonomously.
I think the reason that it hasn't degenerated into chaos
is because we do have human in the loop, but it's more at the functional
or behavior level rather than actual than at the actual code level.
Like we are constantly saying,
we want this kind of behavior expressed within the system.
We've invested a lot
when we were setting it up in end to end behavioral tests and formal modeling
in kind of like the structure of how we wanted the input and the output
from the user visible perspective to be, but not actually at the code perspective.
And I think that layer of human loop is working for us at the moment,
rather than needing to be looking at
every kind of looking more concretely at a PR surface layer.
So when you're going through this process of
writing code, reviewing it and then refining it, writing review it,
refining it.
Have you been able to kind of measure the return on investment at each stage,
and is it like something?
Have you found it
something that kind of diminishes over time and you can say, like,
I don't know, the return of on investment is kind of falling off on a curve or,
or is it or is it not like that? Is it a bit more messy than that?
Yeah.
So, ish.
And the reason I say ish is that I don't think the industry overall
has a really good metric of return on investment for engineering efforts.
Like, people don't agree on PRs as being a good thing for that.
We've had DORA metrics and a bunch of other metrics, SPACE.
I think at 1.2 and a bunch of other ways of trying to assess engineering
return on engineering investment, and we haven't agreed.
So I don't think we're doing better than that.
We're we do.
Where it does make it easier to see, though, is that we know
exactly the costs that go into each task, because it's token cost.
It's not scarce human attention costs that we aren't tracking perfectly.
So we have a much better understanding on that input side.
And so that does allow us to then do experiments in terms of, cool,
Let's swap out a model.
Can we see this same shape of output for cheaper cost
or quicker time to first token or other metrics that we care about.
And then we just kind of say, yeah, PRs are roughly the thing
that we want to be optimizing for and trying to separate out that.
Like, is it actually kind of PRs that make sense or PRs
that are valuable to the company or stuff along those lines
and kind of
just say it's human engineering, and we're going to trust
that human engineers are doing appropriate work,
just like most organizations trust their engineers at the moment.
So I think that's more the way that we're formulating the experimentation.
And the ROI side is by what can we modify on the input side
to try to get the same outcome as what we had before as our baseline?
And normally what we're looking for is cheaper or faster.
And so that might be cool.
Let's improve the context or add a new skill,
or do something else along there and try to make sure that that outcome
is at least stable or better on a quality metric.
Does that make sense?
Yeah, yeah. It's a very. Very difficult.
Sorry.
Microphone.
Very difficult
question to answer because I think like since we've,
you know, since we've actually had to start paying for the AI credits
that we've used, it's become a much more kind of pressing question, actually.
What is the value being derived from each iteration?
Yeah, I think just on that, it's.
There's a whole bunch of cost that is associated
with human attention that isn't categorized.
And so, yes, we now have a line item on a bill that we can optimize against.
But that doesn't mean that it's more expensive just because it's
now showing up as a line item on a bill that wasn't there beforehand.
Yeah.
All right. Yeah. Thanks very much.
Nice. Cool.
So shifting now to look a little bit at the context and environment side.
This is where we do in terms of some of the investments that we do.
This is one of the places that's outside of the agent.
So context, it's everything that's in the repo.
It's everything in your organization.
It's like how you actually do a thing.
And that's how you do a thing that is specific to your kind of style,
to your engineering culture.
If you want just the generic
wisdom of the internet, go ask an agent without any specific context.
If you want an agent, actually do something that is relevant to you.
You need to be feeding it context.
So shared conventions, constraints, tools.
And then importantly,
what is the transmission layer from context that accrues outside of the repo
to get into the repo.
So can we go from Slack and communication and conversations
and incident reports into context in the repo.
That then gets updated so that the agent knows what has happened on Slack,
where people have been asking, why did we do this thing?
What is the historical reason for it?
That wasn't present
when we asked an agent in the first place, which is why we went to
ask our human colleagues.
Or can we pull in Notion docs?
Because that's our source of truth for what architectural decisions are,
for what the current kind of decision is, and how do we get that
into a form that the agent in the repo can be consuming the environment?
The important bit about the environment in my mind is less about,
hey, does it have its dependencies?
It can go download them from the internet.
It's more about can it verify its work?
Can it actually stand up the deps?
Can it stand up mocks of the service? Can it stand up?
Whatever it needs to do in a representative way
to make sure that its work is correct?
And this is where you need to have some human care,
because you can't just tell an agent, go test against production.
You can, actually, but it's just a little bit more risky.
But aged.
The agent doesn't have a knowledge
of what is a representative production workload doesn't know your customers.
It doesn't know what they care about.
It doesn't know their latency constraints.
It doesn't know their preferences.
And so if you give it some data, it will test against that mock data.
If that mock data isn't representative of reality, well, great.
Your agent is doing really thorough verification against the wrong target.
And so that's another area where consistent investments mean that we can
then just go run a thousand agents and choose the result that passes
verification the best, or passes these criteria that we care about the best
because we've invested on that side.
Verification is what makes that delegation
practical, because I don't want to have to care about.
I have to go look at 100 different PRs to choose the best PR.
I want to say, I want to go look at the metadata associated with those
to see which ones are at the highest level of score on quality,
on evaluation, on latency, on performance.
How do we check it?
How do we evaluate it?
And then frankly, how do we then track that against production.
So if we have changes that have caused the production incident,
yeah, we 100% should go look back at the traces of those changes.
We should go look back at that PR review cycle.
We should go look back at how the agent went and did that.
And we can, because, you know, we're storing these agent transcripts
and we're seeing into basically the engineer's head and the decisions
that were made that led to a production out, a production outage.
And so that then gives us a very interesting place to mine,
because if we're investing in that, it's outside of the agent,
but it allows us to create a verification structure
or additional context or additional environment
or something else that gives us confidence that this won't happen again
in the future.
And not just a test, because agents are really good at either faking tests
or getting around tests, or just writing lots and lots of tests.
But whatever.
That higher level invariant that we actually care about is because
the production outage isn't strictly like agent did the wrong thing.
It's normally...
It can be.
Sometimes there's just bugs, but it's normally it violated an invariant
that was implied somewhere else in the system that then caused data
to go bad, or something else as it flows through to go wrong.
Cool.
In terms of kind of that feedback loop, and now we're getting back into kind of
what I think
is one of the more powerful aspects and where kind of the investment should be
is in terms of what that next task kind of inherits.
So this is an example that we had early on in building.
We were constantly churning on our queue.
So we use a durable work queue basically.
Right.
You write a queue item into it once there's only one singleton of that.
So it can't be picked up multiple times.
And we can track kind of the transition of state
through multiple systems as that work as that item gets worked on.
We were constantly stepping on our toes.
And by that I mean agents were constantly stepping on their toes.
So we fix a bug,
then another agent would introduce a bug, and then we'd fix it again,
and then it would get introduced and it was just a mess.
It was the part of our system that being core to
the system was being changed the most in the early days,
and also the part of the system that had the most bugs
and therefore the most agent time spent fixing them.
And so what we did is we built a formal model of it.
So we used Quint and built a formal model of kind of like the basic queue behavior
in terms of putting stuff on, having stuff worked on, taking stuff
off and verifying every single interaction associated with that.
Not something I would have been able to do in a pre-agent world.
Like, I know what formal modeling is.
I wouldn't be able to do it
without sitting down with the textbook for a very long time.
Very easy to go sit down with Opus or Fable and go do that.
So that verification then meant that this part of the system
has been completely stable since we introduced it.
Mind you, it's not the whole system.
It's very small sub part of it, but it's a very small subpart that impacts
every single thing downstream of it.
By no means is our system bug free.
We constantly have bugs that are entirely agent-written,
and we're trying to figure that out.
Like that's part of the learning process for us.
But this part of that has been solid.
And so by investing in the verification of it, by investing in how we're testing
and making sure that this code is correct,
we were able to knock out an entire class of bugs.
And agents are really good at working against an optimization target.
You say, hey, you need to satisfy this held out constraint.
Go figure it out.
They will happily go bang their heads against the wall
until they have something that satisfies that constraint.
And if you're confident, which you should be
because it's formally verified that that constraint is going to hold, well,
then you've got a great thing to go bang the agent's head against the wall.
That isn't just a unit test.
Cool.
In terms of kind of like the metrics and how we're thinking about, like,
I talk a lot about success in terms
of making the system better or removing bugs or what does that mean?
Well, there's we've hit this issue as well
in terms of prior to investing in like a deeper understanding of the system.
And so the key point is like if we just look at run success
and run success here for us is agents set up PR, CI passes.
Well then great.
We can swap out between different models,
between different harnesses, between different approaches.
This is to this is an example
from one of the experiments we did looking at effort levels.
Specifically, this was done with the Claude class of models.
And we first just looked at run success.
So are we passing CI at the end of it.
And high effort costs us more.
It's high effort. Medium effort is cheaper.
And we were seeing equivalence across those two
only by kind of then going and looking level deeper looking at
first review approval rate did we see, oh, high effort
Had a higher first approval rate and medium effort had a lower
first approval rate.
What this means is that it wasn't
just we were just looking initially at the cost of just the implementation.
We had to take into account the cost of the whole system, though,
because we also pay for review.
And so a higher first review approval rate means review is cheaper because
we don't have to pay for
review rounds.
And so only by starting to break out
kind of the different components of our system,
rather than just focusing on
like the coding agent or focusing on the thing
that was actually doing the implementation.
Are we able to start to pick
and decouple and understand where these different interactions are happening?
If we had kind of just looked at this and shipped, the medium effort
or cost would have actually gone up, despite seeing that the headline
costs, the thing that we are focusing on and optimizing for would have gone down.
And I guess mainly the takeaway here is metrics are important.
I don't think that's surprising to anyone, but it's so easy to say yes.
I know metrics are important.
Observability is important, but I think with agents things move so.
fast and it is hard to kind of pay attention to this system.
To the question earlier about like, how do we have human observability
or human loop?
We try to put it in by having observability at the meta layer,
by understanding how the whole system overall
is working through throughput or through latency or through other aspects.
This is more of an example here.
I think, in terms of the interaction mode and the focus on there,
where you can get ROI by thinking less about the agents and more about
how you're interacting with the agent.
This is my example here.
I asked an agent in Slack.
Hey, cool. I've got this PR.
It's stuck in CI.
Why is it taking so long in CI?
Agent came back was saying cool median or sorry
P90 for CI is 15.5 minutes.
Let's go explore a bunch of ways that we can improve CI.
We also have a merge queue.
And so that means that when we want to merge it's not just CI.
It needs to wait in the back of a queue and slowly segment and go up.
We do we do groupings.
Where a couple of PRs land together.
It's to deal with the issue that we had where CI would run effectively
on a branch, but then when it merged into main,
main had already moved and we'd introduce bugs.
So pretty standard reasons when I push back on
that agent and was like, cool, okay, but what about the merge queue?
How is that impacting it?
So the merge queue itself was 52.4 minutes at P90.
That means roughly we were spending 35 minutes sitting in the queue
waiting and then only 15 minutes on CI.
Can you tell me about the distribution?
So you may have P90 at 15 minutes,
but the sort of 91% might be sort of hours and hours and hours.
Do you know what the distribution of.
I don't have the distribution to hand at the moment.
I believe the max that we saw for merge
queue was like two, 2.5 hours kind of thing.
So long.
Because if you have a priority queue, you've got a power
law, whereas if it's random, you get an exponential.
Yeah.
So the way that our queue works, it's, it's there's no prioritization assigned.
It's basically just whatever lands like whatever gets merged next.
So it's just time series.
And I think where most of our issues were coming around
was that we weren't doing a large enough grouping on the stuff that was landing.
And so we were basically constraining ourselves artificially
by saying we were only landing five things at a time,
five things at a time, with five groups in parallel,
when we could be scaling that out both vertically and horizontally.
So when you measured this roughly how many autumns did you did you measure?
Yeah.
So our max queue length hit
60 to 80 in that range.
And we looked at kind of over two weeks of data.
I think that's going to be roughly 1,500 plus
PRs. Yeah.
So a decent chunk.
And so I think
kind of the thing for me here, though, is that,
thinking through like
the question that I given the agent in the first place was poorly specified.
Like, what I really cared about was the merge queue I had asked about.
Kind of CI, though, because I was annoyed by CI at that point in time,
and so only by kind of iterating with the agent in that public surface
in Slack, was I able to get to kind of the number that I did right there.
And so a smarter agent, I don't think would have been able to read my mind
and say, hey, you're actually concerned about merge queue
when I'm specifically asking about CI duration.
And so in that case, it's like, cool.
What is the investment there?
Like we might think that, oh, we're going to be saved by kind of smarter agents.
They're going to just solve our problems in that regard.
But if we're asking for poorly specified things, then yeah,
you're going to get some random results coming out at the end of it.
And so at least the decision that we've made in that I try to kind of embody
in this regard is cool.
Well then let's do that in a public setting.
In Slack, where I can have that conversation
and other folks can chime in in terms of helping me specify
my poorly specified question that I didn't know
was even poorly specified in the first place.
And then it becomes a searchable archive of information
that we can have publicly available.
So now that's context, not context in the repo,
but it's context on Slack that can then feed other agent workflows.
And so that shift in terms of hey, the interaction mode needs to change
in terms of how you're communicating with it to make it more amenable
to further context generation or further context consumption, or more of that
repeated iterative multiplayer flow, I think has benefits this one.
No idea how to measure.
To be clear, I think it's better, but I have no idea how to measure
whether it's making us more efficient or not.
To be talking to the agents in Slack rather than personally on local CLIs.
Cool.
We also think about evidence and so evidence here.
This is where a lot of our ROI kind of stuff comes from.
And frankly, it's on the second to minute timescale.
So a lot of this stuff that is easy to measure is test types.
Lint does a pass, CI does it do kind of the basic things.
That's trivial
because I can run a machine in order to go evaluate it deterministically.
That's not the interesting bit though.
Like what I really care about
is customer outcomes incidents, how much the PR needs to be reworked.
And so the way that we try to think about ROI kind of across this time series or
this time scale is these super expensive figuring out the correlation
between these much less expensive than just measuring this on its own.
And so a lot of the kind of thinking that we do around signals is really
what signals can we derive to think about kind of second cements
that is correlated to minutes, hours, that is correlated to days to weeks.
And we throw off a ton of this data just naturally as an engineering
organization, like we have incidents, we know where those incidents came from,
but then we don't always connect back to the actual agent sessions
that created those incidents or the tests that we're missing, or the link
that was missing,
or the verification function that was missing
that allowed for that incident that happened in the first place.
And so our bet, my bet, is more so
that by focusing on the correlation between these, in terms of figuring out
what bits of tests help lead to better
or rather less review rounds that lead to less
incidents is going to be more valuable to you as an organization,
rather than trying to measure this directly based off your agent transcripts.
Like, it's more and more layers of indirection
and more and more layers of traction, but then just lean into the correlation
and see what happens there.
And trust me, you all have this data.
It's in a bunch of disparate systems.
It's not all in one place, but every organization
and every engineering organization has this data.
They just need to figure out how to correlate it over a bunch of time series.
Second last slide.
So I think the important thing, and this ties back to the earlier example
about kind of looking at the medium versus high
thinking effort is that you got to include the full cost.
And the cost is not just the agent.
You also have to have human attention here.
And so anything you can do to kind of remove the amount of human touch points
that you have on landing code, well, that's really hard to measure.
But if you can do it, that time is really, really expensive.
It's way more expensive than your token bill.
And so figuring out the way to understand that, model
that and then remove it gives you a bunch of ROI on there.
But looking at the full cost.
So retries, reviews, infrastructure, human attention.
And when I say retry there I don't just mean retries on the same task,
but I mean hey, are you doing the same task with different models?
Do you have to go repeat that work because it was poorly done?
Do you have to go change it?
All of that kind of stuff.
That's all the full cost of a PR, the full cost of a feature, and then
cross it against comparable work, like if you're at a larger engineering org.
Yeah, every task is different, but every task is also kind of similar.
Like, yes, the actual task content might be doing a different thing,
but you can do clustering and categorization.
And so you can start to see about kind of trends among those different categories
in those different categories, categories and clusters.
You finally need to
just have some way of being able to say, hey, this is the evidence in terms
of driving the ROI and to the point question earlier about token budgets,
the evidence is what's on the input layer
in terms of the tokens that you're spending.
So it is a little bit, I feel, a bit of a weird calculation
to go spend more money to go save money because, you know, you need to go
spend more, do more experiments to say, hey, this improved our own ROI.
The way that we do this internally is we shadow a lot of our production workload.
And so we'll keep the factory running and we'll choose a subset of tickets
and we'll change the context, change the model,
change the harness, change something and we'll see what the impact of that is,
because we have so many automated gates on quality at the end.
And so then that allows us to see, hey, are these outcomes equivalent.
And then we can measure that input and we can do that because they're agents
and we can go tell them to do wasted work.
They don't know it's wasted. They're just doing work.
Whereas it'd be really hard to go tell a human,
hey, go do something for an experiment, and we're going to throw away the work
with that at the end.
Cool.
Finally, the one reoccurring workflow and this is the loop.
It's define what the acceptable result is like.
That is the verification side.
That is kind of, I think, where a lot of the investment needs to be,
because that allows you to scale.
If you got solid verification, you can scale out input as wide
as you have money to pay for record all of the kind of inputs into that.
So time, cost, human intervention.
Figure out what is the constraint on there and then go improve it
or go change it, or go modify it and then go run it again and again and again.
If you really want to be cool, go simulate your code base.
Go fork it at a specific point in time and start looking at different paths
that it might take.
If you do different models,
like there's lots of different ways that you can kind of take this,
improve one reoccurring constant bit and go make changes
and play forward when you're playing with agent time and not human time.
And so I don't think we know how to do that yet.
We don't do that. To be clear, it's something that we're thinking about.
But that is the kind of opportunities that open up when we've got ROI
that we're defining in terms of tokens,
not in terms of humans that I need to pay to do that.
That's it for me.
I saw some answer questions, though. Yeah.
Clap first.
Can you give us an example of one recurring constraint?
Yeah.
So I think there's a couple things that we think of a better constraint.
One is like the actual like experimental variable.
And so it could be which model we're running.
So Opus 5.5, Opus 5 or 4.8.
And so we do all of this.
We change that and we see what the next set of outcomes are.
And we think of that as a constraint
because that's ultimately what's driving our token cost.
Because they have different token, they have different verbosity assumptions.
They have different require different prompting.
If we want to kind of use Opus 5 specifically, effectively,
we need to change a whole bunch of other things in our context
that requires a whole bunch of associated costs with it that we didn't need to do.
If we just downgraded back to Opus 4.8.
The other way that we think about kind of a constraint is what has caused an agent
to do something poorly, or what is something that is failed at.
And so this might be kind of it can't stand up in the Docker image.
We do we give it it can't stand up Postgres.
And so it can't run any of our database tests.
And so improving that means that it can verify it.
And it means it can go and prove that further on down the line.
As a follow up.
Yeah. Yeah. We'll go to the next person.
Or is it the same.
Is it on the same thing.
Perfect.
How do you know that you're not optimizing
for only that one test that you're running?
Yeah. Very true.
We run lots of tests, and we often like the way that I think
we think about it is that we don't want to just run
a single loop on a single constraint and try to optimize only that.
We've got a whole bunch of things that we're kind of experimenting on
in parallel that are all going to be slightly in tension with each other,
but we think more so that there is a potential state space
of solutions that we are happy with, or kind of constraints,
or operating system or the factory config or whatever you want to define it as.
There's a potential state space that we're okay with,
and as long as we end up somewhere in there, we're good to keep going.
And so the way that I think about it is more along the lines of, cool,
we could either optimize for Opus 5,
but yes, we should optimize for a performance there, and we should optimize
for kind of a review bot having a better time to first
or, sorry, a better a first rate approval.
And we should optimize
for better questions that we get from Slack,
and we should optimize for better verification on this part of the stack.
That has given us a lot of bugs later on and and then and end and end.
And so by kind of having that more holistic view, I think it
by nature prevents us from overfitting on a local minimum,
but we might still end up on a local minimum at some point.
And we'll need to figure out how we kind of get ourselves out of that,
out of that at that point.
So I don't have a better answer than do a lot of experiments,
which are also then expensive.
You mentioned
for modeling, could you kind of take us through a very high level, the process
that you went through to actually integrate that back into the code base?
Yeah. Super simple: yes, Fable.
And but more concretely, I had a list of bugs that we had had
I had a list of issues, and fixes
and then the repeated fixing of the fix and all of that kind of stuff.
And then I worked with an agent to be like, to kind of take
the system in isolation that we work in Python.
And so we basically have a module that has our queue
and that's took the queue.
We then exhaustively went through all of the things that called that queue
categorized the behavior.
And when I say we the agent did it, I was just guiding.
Then we
kind of derived a formal model for it,
made sure that model passed all of the existing tests,
then replayed all of the bugs that had happened against that model
to see whether those bugs would have been valid under it.
And then every time that we have a new bug in that space,
we go check whether the model, the formal model needs to be updated.
And so we then layer on that with property based testing and invariant based
testing in Python native formats
as that kind of like higher level bit on top of it,
so that we can try to catch where kind of assumptions
are drifting away from what our model might assume.
So is very much so that kind of initial exhaustive search space
and then replaying a bunch of bugs, and then how do we maintain and update
and make sure that we're kind of continuing to not just change the code,
but also change the model when we change code that is related to it?
We're also it's a little bit of an easier example,
because that part of the code base doesn't
really change that much anymore after the initial development,
and so haven't really needed to deeply reckon with high pace
change of a formal model in a part of the code base.
We're gonna run this way.
We're gonna cast over here.
Are you with Katherine?
You mentioned earlier that you had some formal models for verification.
Could you give some examples of how you did that?
And then the second question is,
have you benchmarked your coding harness versus others?
Yeah.
So the formal models was what I was just mentioning about Quint.
In terms of verifying like a queue within the system.
And basically the is
go figure out a part of the system that has a bunch of bugs
that is small enough in scope that you can formally verify it.
The issue with formal verification is that it becomes computationally
very expensive once you've got enough state that you need to manage there.
So we had a small bit that had a bunch of bugs and a bunch of issues
that I could sit down and exhaustively figure out
all the ways that it was called and all the state transitions,
and then just built a model off that to play back a bunch of bugs, to
go verify that those bugs would have been invalid under that model,
and make sure that we are updating it moving forward.
So the formal model had to be designed by you?
Designed by an agent that I was working with.
That's based on the
context that was provided.
So if you're talking
of verifying logic, business logic right,
you need to have the domain knowledge encoded into the business logic.
So the verification should follow that model.
So was that the case or did you do some kind of coding level
formalisms that were implemented.
Yeah.
So we had the business logic encoded in code beforehand.
But we were formally we were verifying a part of the system that already existed
and fixing a bug, a bug or two along the way.
Yeah.
And your second, you had another follow up question. Yeah.
Just like benchmarking of the harness itself on coding tasks.
So on benchmarks like SWE-bench or METR or any of the other 100
benchmarks out there.
Yeah.
So we have Tessl Agent, but Tessl Agent is specifically
for kind of like factory tasks.
It's not a general purpose coding agent.
Please don't use it as a coding agent. It is not as good.
It is for higher level things above that.
That's the skills that we ship with it.
And so no, I don't have those because we just use Claude Code or Codex or
whatever the meta one is these days kind of thing.
So we're using like the things that are actually doing work in our factory
are the actual coding agents that are provided by the frontier labs.
Hey, Rob,
this is about perhaps slightly riffing of what you put on.
I seem you wrote it probably called wrote it
about some of the ROI metrics that you think are maybe fiction.
Yeah, but how do you think about
how would you quantify developer experience within the software factory?
And do you see that as a transitional object or as a core objective?
Yeah.
If that makes sense.
Yeah. It does.
So DevEx is hard.
I think is the Corbett,
I it's like, say, I want to answer that
inverse in terms of transitional or core objective,
and then in terms of how we think about measuring it,
I think for the stuff that we are building,
we are more interested in agentic experience than we are in developer experience right
now, because agents are the ones who are mainly interacting with our APIs
or interacting with our skills or interacting with our platform.
And so agentic experience is actually much easier to measure,
because we can spin up an agent's in a box and see whether it does
the thing that we'd expect it
when given a task of shape that we would like,
that we see our customers using in production.
And so that kind of evaluation,
because we can go have a bunch of agents do, it becomes much more tractable.
And so that I think is much more measurable.
However, there is a layer
where we still want humans to enjoy interacting with product.
It can't just be purely optimized for agents.
And also humans do need to interact with tessellations or with other parts
of our product surface.
And I think there we lean much more on kind of qualitative
rather than quantitative measures in terms of listening to what people are saying,
rather than trying to jump straight into kind of quantifying it.
Over time, I imagine that's just partially where we are, the stage of company
that we're at in terms of we have a direct relationship
with the majority of people who are using a product,
particularly in the enterprise setting.
And so we can just go listen, and then by proxy,
like for our internal factory,
all our customers are sitting over there right next to us.
And so they will very happily
come tell us when something's bad or not feeling good.
So I think that's the way that we've been solving it so far.
So thank you so much. Rob.
I'm going to click over.